<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web Security on r00tpunk</title>
    <link>https://r00tpunk.github.io/tags/web-security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web Security on r00tpunk</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://r00tpunk.github.io/tags/web-security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SQL Injection Lab – Lesson 5 (POST parameter injection -error based)</title>
      <link>https://r00tpunk.github.io/posts/learning/less5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://r00tpunk.github.io/posts/learning/less5/</guid>
      <description>POST parameter injection -error based POST-parameter error-based injection is when malicious input in an HTTP POST field deliberately triggers a database/application error that leaks internal info (SQL fragments, column/ table names, DB type/version) in responses or logs.&#xA;Inject parameter So this is our test lab: http://localhost:8080/sqli-labs/sqli-labs-master/Less-12/.&#xA;Now you see we have the login page with the input fields of Username and Password.&#xA;Testing queries Now let&amp;rsquo;s try the simple login which is &amp;ldquo;admin, admin&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL Injection Lab – Lesson 4 (Blind injections - Time based)</title>
      <link>https://r00tpunk.github.io/posts/learning/less4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://r00tpunk.github.io/posts/learning/less4/</guid>
      <description>Blind injections -(Time based) An injection technique where the attacker cannot see the query output directly; instead, they infer information through side‑effects such as time delays or content changes.&#xA;Inject parameter Look for parameters placed inside single quotes: id=&#39;... Confirm the server shows delays or responds immediately. By measuring latency you can infer boolean results and enumerate the database. If the delay happen, parameter is injectable.&#xA;Time-Based Paylods Construction Identify injection point (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL Injection Lab – Lesson 3 (Blind injections - Boolean based)</title>
      <link>https://r00tpunk.github.io/posts/learning/less3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://r00tpunk.github.io/posts/learning/less3/</guid>
      <description>Blind injections -(Boolean based) Blind SQL injection is a technique where the attacker can infer information from the database without seeing the actual query output, using only binary responses.&#xA;With pure blind SQLi the application won’t print database values for you — you can only test true/false.&#xA;Boolean‑based – the injected condition evaluates to TRUE or FALSE.&#xA;Inject parameter Look for parameters placed inside single quotes: id=&#39;... Confirm the app shows errors or returns a page that changes on bad input (even if message hidden — error may still be logged).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL Injection Lab – Lesson 2 (Double Query Injection)</title>
      <link>https://r00tpunk.github.io/posts/learning/less2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://r00tpunk.github.io/posts/learning/less2/</guid>
      <description>Double Query (Sub-Query) Injection Inject parameter Look for parameters placed inside single quotes: id=&#39;... Confirm the app shows errors or returns a page that changes on bad input (even if message hidden — error may still be logged). If the response changes, parameter is injectable. If you get SQL error, good — proceed carefully.&#xA;Dumping database name Payload:&#xA;1&amp;#39; AND (select 1 from (select count(*), concat(0x3a,0x3a,(select database()),0x3a,0x3a, floor(rand()*2))a from information_schema.columns group by a)b) --+ if error shows DataBase name, you succeeded.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL Injection Lab – Lesson 1 (Error-Based: String)</title>
      <link>https://r00tpunk.github.io/posts/learning/less1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://r00tpunk.github.io/posts/learning/less1/</guid>
      <description>What is this Lesson About? This lab demonstrates a classic Error-Based SQL Injection vulnerability.&#xA;The application takes user input from the URL (id parameter) and uses it directly in a SQL query without proper validation or sanitization.&#xA;The purpose of this lesson is to understand how SQL errors can reveal valuable information and how attackers exploit them.&#xA;How to Identify if It Is Error-Based? When testing a parameter for SQL injection, attackers often add characters like:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
